(忆往昔)
敬  跟你们在另一边相见
Here's to running into you guys on the other side.
我上去后  就放你出去
When we get to earth and I release you,
你就能直入天堂
it's an express straight to heaven.
没时间道别
No time for goodbyes.
我是为卡西迪奥而来
I'm here about Castiel.
他的能量还有剩吗
Was there any of his grace left?
问题是  你愿付出代价吗
Question is, are you willing to pay for it?
一定要把他分毫不伤地送回来
He must be returned... intact.
明白了吗
Is that clear?
我上次见你时就说过  我能逃出监狱
Told you last time I saw you I'd get out of the slammer.
我们想知道如何除掉
We need to know how to remove
迪恩手臂上的该隐血印
the Mark of Cain from Dean's arm.
他爆发了
He's gone nuclear!
谁能想到血印会这么厉害
Who knew the mark was so toxic?
我是知道的
Actually, I did.
去除血印的下一步要做什么
What is the next step in removing this mark from my arm?
河流将终结于源头
The river shall end at the source.
如果你再叫我帮忙
If you ever ask me for help again,
我宁愿死
I will choose death.
你会变得更糟的
You're gonna get worse!
-妈妈  -费格斯
- Mommy. - Fergus.
你以为我在摆布你
You think I've been manipulating you.
我可是你母亲
I am your mother, after all.
我们可以做一家人
We can be a family.
我一直在思考  如果我存在的目的
I've been thinking just how wretched it would be
被人剥夺那  我会多么痛苦
if my own raison d'etre...were taken from me.
那么你会为我去找大巫师团吗
Does this mean that you'll go to the grand coven on my behalf?
比那还好
Even better.
我把大巫师团找来给你了
I've brought the coven to you.
你认识奥莉薇特吧
I believe you know Olivette.
你的朋友  温家兄弟
These friends of yours -- the winchesters --
我听说他们是...怎么说的来着
I hear they are, oh, what do you call it, um,
记录者
men of letters?
我跟温家兄弟的关系是我的私事
My relationship with the Winchesters is my business.
我会对付他们  我不会杀了他们
I'll handle them. I'm not killing them.
好吧  亲爱的
All right, deary.
行啊
Of course.
听你的
Whatever you say.
(如今)
[咒语]
鲍比
Bobby?
鲍比  能听到吗
Bobby, can you hear me?
鲍比  我们需要你帮忙
Bobby, we need your help.
萨姆
Sam!
[邪恶力量 第10季第17集]
(24小时前)
萨姆
Sam.
我的故事从我杀死我弟弟开始
My story began when I killed my brother,
你的故事不可避免地  将以此结束
and that's where your story inevitably will end.
嗯
Yeah.
好的  一定过去
Yeah, okay, just, um... just be there.
嗯  得挂了
Yeah. Got to go.
睡得怎么样
How did you sleep?
又香又甜
Like a drunk baby.
有什么情况
What do we got?
没有
Uh, nothing.
真的吗
Really?
是啊
Yeah, I mean, uh,
没有奇怪的死亡事件  或恶魔踪迹
no weird deaths, no demon signs.
有个狐女在博伊西外的
There's a kitsune working some truck stops
卡车休息站害人  但是鲁迪去解决了
outside of Boise, but Rudy's on it, so...
好吧  今天休息
All right. So, uh, snow day.
我们喝个烂醉  然后打游戏如何
I say we get drunk and shoot crap.
只是我们每天都干那个
Yeah, except we do that every day.
其实  我想去看电影
Actually, I was thinking about seeing a movie.
嗯  那也挺好
Yeah, that could be cool.
是法国电影
It's a French movie.
有裸戏吗
You mean like nudie French?
比那还好
Even better.
是讲一个哑剧演员  他其实是只蟑螂
It's about a mime that's secretly a cockroach.
没懂
I-I don't get it.
《纽约时报》说
Dude, the New York Times said...
谁管他们
Who cares?
好吧  威奇托在公映
All right, well... it's playing in Wichita,
我可能会看个通宵
so I might not be back till morning.
我相信你  别犯错误
Well, I trust you. Make good choices.
嗯
Right.
我其实不非得自己去的
You know, I mean... I don't have to go alone...
没事的
It's fine.
再说  我正好可以一个人歇歇
Besides, I could use a little "me" time.
好吧  别进我房间
All right. Stay out of my room.
当然
Totally.
谢谢你能来  小卡
Thanks for coming, Cass.
当然  迪恩呢
Of course. Where's Dean?
我就是为了迪恩
This is about Dean.
他...
Is he...?
他情况越来越糟了
He's getting worse.
小卡  我们已经考虑了其他所有的选择
Cass, we've gone through every other option possible.
-我们得考虑...  -别说出来
- We got to talk about... - Don't say it.
你以为我想吗
Do you think I want this?
我也不乐意
I'm not a fan of it, either.
但如果我们想除去血印
But if we want to get rid of the mark...
查理完全没消息
I'm just saying Charlie's gone radio silent,
我们其他一切尝试都不奏效
everything else we've tried has been a dead end.
所以...
So...
我开车
So I'll drive.
-上帝啊  -得了  你又不是没见过
- God. - Please. It's nothing you haven't seen before.
你是我妈妈  我什么都不想见到
You're my mother. I don't want to see anything.
我下过地狱了  谢谢
I've been to hell, thanks.
下次  敲门
Next time, knock.
这是我的地盘  我不敲门
This is my domain. I don't knock.
有事吗  费格斯
Did you want something, Fergus?
我是克劳...
It's Crow--
算了
Forget it.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
什么意思
What do you mean?
你这几周一直喋喋不休地烦我
I mean you've been nattering constantly at me for weeks,
而这几天你都没来烦过我
and now you haven't annoyed me for days.
你在谋划什么
You're up to something.
没错
You're right.
我在跟人约会
I'm seeing someone.
我是个女人  有欲求
I'm a woman. I have desires,
有需要的  特伦特他...
needs, and Trent is...
特伦特
Trent?
你在跟...一个叫特伦特的约会
You're dating a... Trent?
他是比格森快餐店的副经理
He's an assistant manager at Biggerson's.
虽不是特别聪明
He's not the brightest bulb,
但他很...
but he's so...
坚实
...firm.
别说了
Please stop talking.
是你问的
You asked.
穿好衣服吧
Just put some clothes on.
鲁迪  鲁迪  听我说
Rudy. Rudy! Hey, look.
我知道你自己能解决
I know you can handle it, okay?
我就是想说
I'm just saying that, uh, you know,
你如果需要人帮个忙  我可以...
if you needed a little assist, I could, uh, you know...
好吧  好啦
All right. All right, all right, all right.
冷静  我不该问
Chill out. Sorry I asked.
你了解我的
You know me.
我一向都好
I'm always good.
我好极了
Hey, I'm fan-damn-tastic.
够近了  卡西迪奥
That's far enough, Castiel.
什么
Excuse me?
我有命令  你不能上楼
I have orders. You aren't allowed upstairs.
谁的命令
Says who?
请稍等
Hold, please.
你好  卡西迪奥
Hello, Castiel.
汉娜
Hannah.
我曾发誓再不占据皮囊
I swore I'd never occupy another vessel,
但这事得当面谈
but...we need to have this conversation face-to-face.
什么事
What conversation?
你上天堂想要什么
What do you want in heaven?
梅塔特隆
Metatron.
为什么
Why?
是为了你的能量吗  你在衰弱吗
Is this about your grace? Are you fading?
我现在还没事
I'm fine for now.
是为了我哥哥
This is about my brother.
因为你们认为梅塔特隆
Because you think Metatron
可能有关于该隐血印的信息吗
might have information about the Mark of Cain?
不  我们确定他知道
No. We know he does.
那是他一面之词  他会撒谎的
So he says. But Metatron lies.
汉娜  我们只想跟他谈谈
Hannah, we just want to talk with him.
不  你们想找他帮忙
No, you want his help.
但我们都知道  梅塔特隆一定会
But we both know the only way Metatron helps you
开出出狱的价码
is if he's free.
我不能放书记员出狱
And I can't let the scribe out of his cell.
不能有第二次了  他太危险了
Not again. He's too dangerous.
-我们不会的  -你会的
- We won't... - Yes, you will.
因为你已经无路可走了
Because you're desperate.
我为天堂做了那么多
After all I've done for heaven...
我为你做了那么多
...after all I've done for you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你是该觉得抱歉
You should be.
小卡  走吧
Cass, let's go.
怎么  我们走吗
What? We're leaving?
我们打不过四个天使
Yeah, we can't fight off four angels.
那怎么  你就放弃找梅塔特隆了吗
So... so what? You just want to give up on Metatron?
不  我们需要他
No, we need him.
该执行B计划了  我们要劫狱
Time for plan "B". We break him out.
我听说  你负责掌管地狱的总机
I'm told you run hell's switchboard.
很辛苦啊
Tough job.
还行吧
It's not so bad.
我很乐意尽职
I'm just happy to do my part.
你真是只恶魔吗
You sure you're a demon?
被诅咒之人也可以是本分的员工
Y-you can be damned and a conscientious worker.
去年  我儿子  克劳力
Well, last year, my son...Crowley,
被温家兄弟劫走了
was taken by the Winchesters.
我需要知道他们当时把他关在了哪
I need to know where they were holding him,
我得知他当时打过恶魔电话
and I'm told he made a call.
我想拜托你帮我追查
I was hoping you could trace it for me.
当然
O-of course.
您是太后嘛
Y-you are the queen mother.
他是打过
H-h-he did call,
但当时有干扰
but t-there was some i-interference.
我无法确定精确位置
I-I can't get the exact location.
10英里半径范围内可以吗
W-would a 10-mile radius work?
我将就一下吧
I'll make do.
好棒
Yeah.
多尼
Hey, Donnie.
伙计
Hey, man.
给我来道赫夫·维勒查泽
I'll do the, uh, Hervé Villechaize.
-好嘞  -谢了
- You bet. - Thanks.
(萨姆)
给钱吧  废柴
Money. Now. Loser.
多谢
Gracias.
钱拿来  快点  马上
Give me your cash. Now. Right now.
那些不入流的小子怎么回事
What's up with the abercrombie rejects?
大学生来"体验生活"了
College kids "slumming it."
这什么话嘛
Slumming? What are you talking about?
这馆子多好
This is a nice joint, huh?
你还有定制的小便球呢
You got those custom urinal pucks.
好了  接下来谁上
Come on, bitches. Who's next?
20块一局
20 bucks a game.
20块
20 bucks.
那个  我玩吧
Yo! Yeah, I'll, uh... I'll play.
-不是吧  -哥们  他喝醉了
- What, seriously? - Dude, he's blitzed.
不不  我挺好的
No. No, no, no, no. I'm... I'm... I'm fine, man.
我可以玩的
I'm good to go.
没问题的
Good to go.
他是没事  拿球杆吧
He's fine. Grab a stick.
50年代的时候
So, back in the '50s,
奥利弗·普莱斯是个灵童
Oliver Pryce was a kid psychic.
他到处表演
He performed everywhere...
嘉年华  大西洋城  等等
Carnivals, Atlantic City... you name it.
他是真有天赋
He was the real deal.
记录者教过他
Now, the men of letters were teaching him
控制自己的能力  但后来他们...
how to control his powers when they got... you know.
惨遭屠杀
Brutally slaughtered?
重点是  他是好人
The point is, he's one of the good guys.
他可能乐意见我们
He might be happy to see us.
也可能不乐意
Or not.
(私人领地  闯入者将遭到起诉)
(勿入)
普莱斯先生
Mr. Pryce?
奥利弗·普莱斯
Oliver Pryce!
我把门撞开
I'll break it down.
伙计  冷静
Dude, dude, dude. Chill.
怎么了  我是想帮忙
What? I'm helping.
听我的
Just follow my lead.
普莱斯先生
Mr. Pryce?
我是萨姆
This is Sam...
温彻斯特
Winchester.
你是萨姆·温彻斯特  记录者
You're Sam Winchester, man of letters.
嗯  你怎么知道...
Yeah. H-how did you, uh...
我会读心  记得吗
Mind reader, remember?
你是...
And you're...
你是什么
What are you?
我是个天使
I'm an angel.
什么
That...
不可能
No, you can't be.
为什么
Why not?
因为我是无神论者
Because I'm an atheist.
今后不是了
Not anymore.
那是你吗
That's you?
是以前的我
Was me.
我现在不做灵媒了
I don't do the psychic stuff no more.
跟人待在一起  很折磨人
Being around people, it's kind of...hell.
他们脑子吵个不停
All those brains yapping all the time
能把人逼疯
drives a guy bananas.
因为你能听到每个人的想法
Because you can hear everyone's thoughts.
听不到你的
Well, not yours.
我只能从你那儿看到颜色
All I'm getting from you is...colors.
但这个嬉皮士
But the hippie over here?
我看到了一个猥琐的霍比特人模样的家伙
I'm seeing some creep-ass hobbit-lookin' fella,
还有监狱
A prison cell?
那是天堂监狱
That's heaven's jail.
天堂还有监狱啊
Heaven's got a freakin' jail?
是啊  没错
Yeah. Yeah, it does.
我们想帮个人越狱
And we're looking to break someone out of it.
好吧
Okay.
我们有个内应
We have an inside man,
但我们需要你帮我们联系他
but we need your help to talk to him.
如果我拒绝呢
And if I say no?
你会读心啊
You're the mind reader.
我去拿东西
I'll get my crap.
我能打到  能打到的
I'll get it. I'll get it.
好样的
There it is.
底袋
Corner pocket.
桌球之王啊
The king is here.
好吧  再来啊
Okay, all right. Again?
好啊
Sure.
这次赌一百吧
Say $100 this time.
嗯  赌三百吧
Yeah. Make it $300.
怎么样
What do you say?
现金给我
Give me your cash.
你好像不够啊
I think you're a little short there.
把表也压上吧  那就行了
Why don't you toss in the watch? Good to go.
这表是我爸给我的
My dad gave me this watch.
肯定有段感人的故事
I'm sure it's a very touching story.
眼泪都要下来了
Got a little tear in my eye.
快点  玩不玩了
Come on. We gonna play or not?
摆球
Rack 'em.
有死者的物件吗
You got anything that belonged to the deceased?
有  这里
Yes. Right here.
很好
Good.
闭嘴  牵手
Now shut up and hold hands.
[咒语]
鲍比
Bobby?
鲍比  能听到吗
Bobby, can you hear me?
鲍比  我们需要你帮忙
Bobby, we need your help.
萨姆
Sam!
底袋
That one.
你算计我
You hustled me.
喷那么多发胶  古龙水
Well, you're pretty quick for a guy
也没喷傻嘛
who's all hair gel and body spray.
谢了  伙计们
Thanks, fellas.
得了  伙计们  他就一混蛋
Forget it, dude. He's an ass.
你们好啊  小伙子们
Hello, boys.
事情就是这样
And, uh, that's what's been happening...
至少长话短说就是这样了
The short version of it, anyway.
还在吗  鲍比
You still there, Bobby?
是的  萨姆
Yeah, Sam.
就是
It's just...
能听到你的声音太好了
real good to hear your voice.
我也很高兴
Yeah, you, too.
好吧
Okay.
如果我没理解错
If, uh, I'm understanding right,
你要想办法去掉迪恩的该隐血印
you got to figure a way to get the Mark of Cain off Dean
免得他再变回恶魔
before it turns him back into a demon?
差不多吧
Pretty much, yeah.
那么又是普通的一天喽
So, just another day at the office for you boys, huh?
让迪恩来说话
Put Dean on the line.
迪恩不在
Dean's not here.
为什么
Why not?
迪恩...
We-- Dean's, um...
他现在状况不太好  鲍比
He's not in a good place right now, Bobby.
那怎么办
So what's the play?
天堂的每个灵魂都锁在自己的隔间里
Each soul in heaven is locked in its own private paradise.
你现在就在隔间里  你得逃出来
That's where you are now. You need to escape.
你得找到通往人间的门  并开启它
You need to find the gate to earth and open it.
然后我们去找梅塔特隆
Then you and I will find Metatron,
上帝的书记员
the scribe of God.
萨姆
Hey, Sam,
还记得当年这份工作就只是
you remember when this job was just
杀怪驱鬼的日子吗
chopping up some fang and tossing back a cold one?
我好怀念啊
I miss that.
我也是
Ditto.
那我逃出去之后
So, while I'm playing Steve McQueen,
会有人找我吗
anyone gonna be looking for me?
所有人都会找你
Everyone.
天使不喜欢有灵魂乱跑
The angels will not like a soul wandering free.
有办法拖住他们吗
We got a way to slow them down?
没有  但是
Not exactly. But, um, you'll...
你肯定会有办法的  鲍比  你一向可以
you'll figure something out, Bobby. You always do.
听我说  多谢抬举
Listen, I appreciate the warm fuzzy, but
但我如今已经不过打打杀杀的日子了
I ain't exactly playing on the big leagues these days.
我一般也就喝喝酒  读读名著
I'm mostly drinking and reading the classics.
老实说  我都生疏了
Truth is, I'm rusty.
或许有更好的人选呢
And maybe there's somebody better out there.
没有了  鲍比
There isn't, Bobby.
加上迪恩现在的样子
And w-with Dean the way he is...
我们没别的办法了
...this is all we got.
我都已经死了
Hell, I'm already dead.
还能坏到哪去
What's the worst that could happen?
迪恩
Dean.
罗威娜
Rowena?
你这样的好女人在这里做什么
What's a nice girl like you doing in a place like this?
抱歉  我说"好女人"了吗
I'm sorry. Did I say "nice girl"?
我是想说"恶魔婊子"
I meant "evil skank""
听你口气好像那是骂人
You say that like it's an insult.
好女人  她们多可悲
But nice girls, they're pathetic.
恶魔婊子才好呢
Here's to evil skanks.
伙计们  她把你们怎么了
Whoa, fellas. What did she do to you?
某人挺厉害啊
Someone's tougher than he looks.
那可不是
You have no idea.
不可能
Not possible.
你在这儿干什么
What the hell are you doing here?
救我儿子
Saving my son.
你儿子
Your son?
克劳力
Crowley.
我认识那个克劳力吗
Crowley Crowley?
我儿子是个国王  是神
My son is a king, a god...
可偏偏因为你
or he would be if you didn't...
你弹个指响
you snap your fingers,
他就会像哈巴狗一样跑过来
and he comes running like a wee lapdog.
女士  我不知道你在说什么
Lady, I don't know what you're talking about.
你把他往正道上带
You're a good influence on him.
所以你必须死
That's why you need to die.
抱歉你的灯光秀没起作用
Well, sorry your little light show didn't work.
我会再努力的
Oh, I'll try again.
怎么  你以为我会放你走吗
What, you think I'm just gonna let you walk out of here?
我认为  你是个英雄
I think you're a hero.
你本可杀了那几个人
You could have killed those men,
但你没杀  因为他们是无辜者
but you didn't because they're innocent.
因为你是好人
'cause you're the good guy,
你想救他们
and you want them to live.
但我施的咒  会吞噬他们
But the spell I cast will devour them
就像那个女孩一样  被从内吞噬掉
from the inside out like it did that girl.
[咒语]
你对她做了什么
What did you do to her?
只有我能救他们
I'm the only one that can save them.
怎么样  英雄
What's it going to be... hero?
我们怎么做
So, where do we start?
你得找到你的天堂的逃生口
You need to find your heaven's escape hatch.
是一样不对劲的东西
Look for something that shouldn't be there,
那就是你的出口
and that's your way out.
我还以为已经退出江湖
Just when I thought I was out
他们又把我拉了回去
they pull me back in.
(罗伯特·辛格)
(罗伯托·辛格)
该死
Balls!
约会不顺利啊  妈妈
Rough date, mother?
这是迪恩·温彻斯特干的
Dean Winchester did this to me.
出去
Get out.
是  陛下
Yes, sir.
你为什么要靠近迪恩·温彻斯特
Why were you anywhere near Dean Winchester?
我想杀了他
I was trying to kill him.
我也试过
Been there.
可是向来不如愿啊
Never seems to work out quite the way you want.
我施的咒本该把他撕得粉碎
The spell I cast should have ripped him apart, but...
简直像是上天在庇护迪恩
It was like Dean was protected from on high.
是该隐血印
It's the Mark of Cain.
不会让宿主轻易死去
It never lets its host die easy.
血印
The mark?
那就是个诅咒
It's just a curse.
是第一个诅咒
T-the first curse.
但也是能去除的
But still, it can be removed.
怎么去除
How?
我会想办法的
I'll find a way.
你想吧
You do that.
你这么作死是有原因的吧
I assume you had a reason for this little suicide run of yours.
有最好的原因  你
The best reason... you.
那俩混蛋一直牵着你鼻子走
Those tumshies have you on a leash.
我以为如果他们死了
I thought I-if they were gone, you...
我知道你怎么想的
I know what you thought.
我也知道你错了
And I know that you were wrong.
萨姆和迪恩现在的状况正合我意
I have Sam and Dean exactly where I want them.
怎么说的
What do they say?
朋友留在身边  敌人摆在眼前
Friends close, enemies closer.
或许他们曾经是你的敌人
Maybe they were your enemies once.
但如今呢  得了吧
But now? Please.
你在意迪恩·温彻斯特打伤了你妈妈吗
Do you even care that Dean Winchester mutilated your mother?!
那是你自己犯蠢
Because you were stupid.
因为我爱你
Because I love you.
如果我的痛苦还不够
Well, if my suffering's not enough,
你也知道恶魔多爱嚼舌头根
you know how much demons gossip.
现在  这事就已经传出去了
Right now, word's already spreading about all this.
如果你无所作为  会显得懦弱
If you do nothing, you'll look weak.
你的子民会开始质疑你  嘲笑你
Your subjects will start to doubt you, mock you.
用不了多久
Then it's just a matter of time
你手下就会造反
before you have a revolt on your hands,
你就会丢掉王位
before you lose your throne.
你在玩一个很危险的游戏
You're playing a dangerous game.
而如今轮到你出手了
And it's your move.
你不能杀了迪恩  好吧
So you can't kill Dean. Fine.
那就把他抓起来
Take him,
扔进哪个阴冷潮湿的牢房  让他烂掉吧
throw him in some dank cell, let him rot.
但你一定要有所行动啊
But do something!
别再拖了  也别找借口了
No more stalling. No more excuses.
让他们看看你有多强大
Show them how strong you really are.
拿出个王的样子来
Be a bloody king!
你确定他能搞定吗
You sure he can handle this?
他可是鲍比  他什么都能搞定
He's Bobby. He can handle anything.
什么
What?
查清怎么会发生这种事
Find out how this happened.
抱歉了  先生们
Excuse me, gentlemen.
先生们...还有女士
Gentlemen...and lady,
请各位镇定地  有秩序地
I need you to return to your heavens
回到你们的天堂
in a calm, orderly manner.
是嘛  凭什么听你的
Oh, yeah? Well, who made you boss?
是吧
Right?
-你以为自己算哪根葱  -我们上
- Who the hell you think do you are? - Let's go.
等等  先生们  女士
Hold off, gentlemen and lady.
先生们  冷静点
Gentlemen, easy.
拜托了
Please!
一直等着你呢
Been waiting on you.
小松鼠
Squirrel.
你娘呢
Boris. Where's Natasha?
她来不来重要吗
Would it make a difference?
不
Not really.
我们还动不动手了
So, we gonna do this?
鲍比们正在反击
The Bobbys are fighting back.
全体支援  我们需要全体支援
All hands. We need all hands.
他们很粗暴  重复  鲍比们很粗暴
They're surly. I repeat, the Bobbys are surly.
假如我找到了出去的路  然后呢
If I find a way out, then what?
通往人间的门是...
The gate is behind door number...
42号
欢迎加入
Welcome to the party.
监狱就在附近了
The prison, it's, uh -- it's close.
小卡  迪恩在哪里
Cass, where's Dean?
什么
What?
你听见了
You heard me.
迪恩...他在休息
Dean's, uh -- he's resting.
他...病了  而且
He's...sick, and --
编个可信点的
Try again.
迪恩不知道我们在干这个
Dean doesn't know we're doing this.
果然是温家人的一贯作风
Well, that's a page right out of the Winchester playbook, ain't it?
迪恩放弃了
Dean has given up.
而你们这俩傻瓜没有
And you idjits haven't.
你会放弃吗
Would you?
当然不会
Hell, no.
听着  我不是说
Look, I'm not saying
我不想把那女巫大卸八块
that I didn't want to slice and dice the witch.
我只是说当时事情不是那样的
I'm just saying that that's not how it went down.
那么是她说谎了
So she's a liar.
一定是家族遗传
Must run in the family.
我妈说那个血印只不过是个诅咒
Mother says that mark is just a curse,
是可以去掉的
can be removed.
当然了  她不知道要如何去掉
Of course, she doesn't know how.
我猜也是
Figures.
但是我挺好的  不劳你费心
But I'm good, thanks.
现在谁在说谎了
Who's the liar now?
她说我变软弱了
She says I've gone soft.
的确
You have.
怎么了
What?
是啊  也许是因为萨姆
Yeah, maybe it's all the human blood
往你体内注射的人血
that Sammy pumped into you, you know?
也许...
Maybe it's, uh --
我不知道  我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
但原先那个克劳力
But the old Crowley,
他会带着地狱猎犬和恶魔来这里
he would have come in here with hellhounds and demons,
会炸飞这小酒馆
and he would have blown the roof off the joint.
如今呢
Now?
你不想干架了  你想聊天
You didn't want to fight. You wanted to talk.
也许我也变了
And maybe I've changed, too.
我在这儿扮心理医生  听地狱之王倾诉
Here I am playing Dr. Phil to the king of hell.
没想到会有这么一天
Never saw that coming.
也许是我们老了
Maybe we're getting old.
我也从没想过我会老
Never saw that coming, either.
到底怎么了
What is it, huh?
为什么你要让亲爱的妈咪困扰你呢
Why you letting mommy dearest tie you into knots?
因为...我们是一家人
Because... we're family.
血亲
Blood.
家人和血缘可不是一回事
That's not the same thing.
一位智者曾告诉我"家人不止于血亲"
A wise man once told me, "Family don't end in blood."
有血缘也不一定是家人
But it doesn't start there, either.
家人关心你
Family cares about you,
而不是关心你能为他们做什么
not what you can do for them.
无论好坏  家人会一直陪在你身边
Family's there through the good, bad -- all of it.
他们会支持你...
They got your back...
无论艰难险阻
even when it hurts.
那才是家人
That's family.
你妈是这样的吗
That sound like your mother?
你好啊  伙计们
Well, howdy, fellas.
这就是上帝的书记员吗
This is the scribe of god?
他看上去像个玩具木偶
He looks like a fraggle.
我会把这话当成是恭维
I'm gonna take that as a compliment.
那可是部极其优秀的电视剧
That was an excellent program.
梅塔特隆  我们来这里...
Metatron, we are here --
我知道你们为何而来  屁西迪奥
I know why you're here, "Asstiel,"
我不感兴趣
and I'm not interested.
我告诉过你  我宁愿死
I told you I would rather die
也不愿让迪恩·温彻斯特
than let Dean Winchester
再拿我当出气筒
use me as his personal punching bag again.
别担心  和迪恩无关
Don't worry. Dean's not involved.
你要做我的出气筒
You're gonna be my punching bag.
备用团队
The "B" Team, huh?
有意思
Interesting.
钥匙在那边
Keys are over there.
快点呀
Chop chop!
你确定只有这个办法
Are you sure this is the only way?
很不幸  是的
Unfortunately.
萨姆棒棒
Sam-tastic!
想我了吗
Miss me?
闻到了吗
Oh, smell that?
自由的味道
That smells like freedom.
我们走
Well, let's go.
我要坐前排
I call shotgun!
你没资格提要求  梅塔特隆
You don't get to make demands, Metatron.
你说了不算
You're not in charge here.
恐怕我说了算  我了解血印
Oh, I'm afraid I am. I know about the mark.
我有你的能量
I have your grace.
规矩我来定
I make the rules.
这叫做筹码  孩子们
It's called leverage, boys.
掌握  运用  逍遥得意
Learn it, live it, love it.
你的能量在我们这里  梅塔特隆
We have your grace, Metatron.
现在你是凡人
You're mortal now.
所以你要回答我们的问题
So you will answer our questions,
否则萨姆会...
or Sam will, um...
怎么说的
What's the phrase?
把你脑浆爆出来
Blow your fricking brains out.
这叫做筹码  梅塔特隆
It's called leverage, Metatron.
掌握  运用  逍遥得意
Learn it, live it, love it.
我们怎么除掉血印
How do we get rid of the mark?
我不知道
I-I don't know.
I don't know!
这是古老的魔法  上帝级的魔法
No, I-it's old magic -- god-level magic.
或者路西法级别的
Or Lucifer level,
但你们不能问他  不是吗
but you can't ask him, exactly, can you?
石碑呢
What about the tablets?
没有  石碑上没有关于血印的记载
No, th-there's -- there's nothing in them about the mark.
那么你说
So when you said
"河水终结于源头"  那只是...
"The river ends at the source," That was --
是我编的胡话
I was just making up crap,
争取时间  好坑你们
trying to buy time till I could screw you over.
不
No.
怎么  之前成功过
What?! It worked before.
他说的是实话
He's telling the truth.
什么
What?
开枪打他
Shoot him.
不不  不  你的能量
No, no! No. Your grace.
我没说谎
I wasn't lying about that.
还有剩
There's still some left.
我带你去找
I'll take you to it.
你决定  小卡
It's your call, Cass.
好了吗
Is it done?
我们完了
We're done.
收拾你的东西滚出去
Get your things and get out.
你不是说真的吧
You aren't serious.
非常认真
Deadly.
但我是你母亲
But I'm your mother.
也许是你带我来到这个世界
You may have brought me into this world,
但你从未做过我的母亲
but you were never my mother.
那么你选了温家兄弟
So you're choosing the Winchesters.
我选择我
I'm choosing me.
我容忍你的谎言
I put up with your lies,
你可悲的小阴谋  是因为
your sad little schemes because...
不对
No.
因为也许你是对的
Because maybe you were right.
也许我不再犀利了
Maybe I did lose my edge.
但今后不会了
But that ends now.
告诉我  罗威娜
Tell me, Rowena,
如果我不是地狱之王
if I were not the king of hell,
你还会假装关心我吗
would you have ever bothered to pretend to care about me?
你不可以
You -- you can't.
我可以
I can.
我可是克劳力
I'm bloody Crowley!
我是地狱之王
I'm the king of hell.
我想什么时候做什么就做什么
I do what I want, when I want.
我不听从你的命令
And I don't take orders from you.
你所拥有的一切
Everything you have,
我会看着它烧成灰
I will watch it burn!
我给你五分钟
I'll give you five minutes.
之后  祈祷我不会再见到你吧
After that, pray I don't see you again.
电影怎么样
How was the movie?
法语的
French.
你呢  你昨晚做了什么
What about you? What did you do last night?
打了桌球  挺无聊的
Played some pool. It was kind of boring.
-好吧  我去梳洗一下  -嗯
- All right. I'm gonna clean up. - Yeah.
小心点
Careful.
萨姆
Sam.
鲍比让我把这个给你
Bobby asked me to give you this.
萨姆
Sam...
这样挺奇怪的吧
So...this is weird, huh?
我是想说
Look, I just wanted to say that
小卡告诉了我你在为迪恩做的事
Cass told me what you're doing for Dean.
我不拦你
And I'm not asking you to stop,
但也许背着他做这些不是好主意
but maybe going behind his back ain't the best idea.
你哥哥  他有时很固执
Your brother, he can be stubborn.
但我觉得他会理解
But I think he'd understand.
我知道这份生活就是如此
And I know it's the life --
做点坏事  才能做更多好事
doing a little bad so you can do a lot of good.
但有时坏事非常严重
But sometimes the bad's real bad
而好事
And the good --
要付出相当大的代价
it can come at one hell of a price.
我不是当事人
I ain't there on the ground,
不管你做什么
and whatever you do,
我知道你会做出正确的选择
I know you'll make the right choice.
你是个好人  萨姆·温彻斯特
You're a good man, Sam Winchester --
最好的人之一
One of the best.
我很为你感到骄傲  孩子
And I'm damn proud of you, son.
我在上面本来挺满足
I was content up here.
但得到你的消息
But getting the call from you,
是很久以来最让我开心的事
it's the happiest I've been in forever,
不管代价如何
no matter what it costs.
注意安全  继续战斗
So stay safe, keep fighting,
狠狠反击
and kick it in the ass.
鲍比
Bobby.